[{"stack":[],"graph":[],"linkedlist":[],"trie":[],"queue":[],"hash":[],"segtree":[],"tree":[{"question":"which of the following statement's are false?","snippet":"1.every graph is a tree\n2.every tree is a graph\n3.all trees are acyclic \n4.all graphs are acyclic ","option_01":"2,4","option_02":"3,4","option_03":"1,3","option_04":"2,3","answer":"1","explaination":""},{"question":"which of the following  are false about tree data structure ?","snippet":"1.each node can have atmost 2 children .\n2.all leaf nodes are at same level.\n3.a tree can have multiple root's\n4.a tree is always connected ","option_01":"1,2,3","option_02":"1,3,4","option_03":"1,2","option_04":"4","answer":"1","explaination":""},{"question":"which of the following sorting algorithm is best for already sorted array?","snippet":"","option_01":"Merge sort","option_02":"Quick sort","option_03":"heap sort","option_04":"Insertion sort","answer":"4","explaination":""},{"question":"which of the following algorithms uses divide and conquer approach?","snippet":"","option_01":"Kadanes algorithm","option_02":"two pointer","option_03":"merge sort","option_04":"selection sort","answer":"3","explaination":""},{"question":"what will be the sizeof(node) in the following code snippet considering an architecture that uses 4Bytes for int and 2Bytes for char ?","snippet":"\nunion node{\nint arr1[2];\nchar ch[3];\nint arr2[3];\nint a;\n}; ","option_01":"12","option_02":"30","option_03":"4","option_04":"6","answer":"1","explaination":""},{"question":"what will be the sizeof(node) in the following code snippet considering an architecture that uses 4Bytes for int and 2Bytes for char ?","snippet":"\\n\nstruct node{\nint arr1[2];\nchar ch[3];\nint arr2[3];\nint a;\n};","option_01":"12","option_02":"30","option_03":"4","option_04":"6","answer":"2","explaination":""},{"question":"which of the following is true about Tree data structure ?","snippet":"1.tree has a cycle\n2.tree is a hierarchical data structure \n3.each node can have atmost 2 children ","option_01":"1","option_02":"2","option_03":"3","option_04":"None","answer":"2","explaination":""}],"array":[{"question":"predict the output of the following code snippet","snippet":"#include<iostream>\nusing namespace std;\nint main()\n{\nint arr[]={1,2,3,4};\nint a=sizeof(arr)/sizeof(arr[0);\nprintf(\"%d\",a);\n}","option_01":"1","option_02":"2","option_03":"3","option_04":"4","answer":"4","explaination":""},{"question":"predict the output of the following code snippet","snippet":"#include<iostream>\nusing namespace std;\nint main()\n{\nint arr[]={1,3,10,-4,-5};\nint a=arr[2]-arr[1];\nprintf(\"%d\",a);\n}\n","option_01":"14","option_02":"2","option_03":"-2","option_04":"7","answer":"4","explaination":""},{"question":"predict the output of the following code snippet","snippet":"#include<iostream>\nusing namespace std;\nint main()\n{\nint arr[]={2,3,4,2,1};\nprintf(\"%d\",arr[2]);\n}\n","option_01":"4","option_02":"2","option_03":"-2","option_04":"7","answer":"1","explaination":""},{"question":"select the true statement among the following about Array data structure","snippet":"","option_01":"indexing starts from 0 in all programming languages","option_02":"stores elements in contiguous memory location","option_03":"can only store homogenous data types","option_04":"deletion takes place in O(1) time considering worst case","answer":"2","explaination":""},{"question":"What is the average of first five multiples of 12\n","snippet":"","option_01":"36","option_02":"38","option_03":"40","option_04":"42","answer":"1","explaination":""}]},{"time":[],"space":[],"sort":[],"search":[],"recursions":[],"greedy":[]}]